Usage: vpkeditcli [--help] [--output VAR] [--type VAR] [--no-progress] [--version VAR] [--chunksize VAR] [--compression-method VAR] [--compression-level VAR] [--gen-md5-entries] [--add-file VAR...]... [--add-dir VAR...]... [--remove-file VAR]... [--remove-dir VAR]... [--preload VAR...] [--single-file] [--extract VAR] [--gen-keypair] [--file-tree] [--sign VAR] [--verify-checksums VAR] [--verify-signature] [--decryption-key VAR] path

This program currently has seven modes:
 - Pack:     Packs the contents of a given directory into a new pack file.
 - Extract:  Extracts files from the given pack file.
 - Generate: Generates files related to VPK creation, such as a public/private keypair.
 - Modify:   Edits the contents of the given pack file.
 - Preview:  Prints the file tree of the given pack file to the console. Can also be combined
             with Pack mode to print the file tree of the new pack file.
 - Sign:     Signs an existing VPK. Can also be combined with Pack mode to sign the new VPK.
 - Verify:   Verify the given pack file's checksums and/or signature. If used together with
             Pack or Sign modes, it will verify the pack file after the other modes are finished.
Modes are automatically determined by the <path> argument, as well as the other given arguments
when it is still unclear. Almost all modes are compatible with each other, and will run in the
most logical sequence possible.

Positional arguments:
  path                      (Pack)     The directory or response file to pack the contents of into a new pack file.
                            (Extract)  The path to the pack file to extract the contents of.
                            (Generate) The name of the file(s) to generate.
                            (Modify)   The path to the pack file to edit the contents of.
                            (Preview)  The path to the pack file to print the file tree of.
                            (Sign)     The path to the VPK to sign.
                            (Verify)   The path to the pack file to verify the contents of. [required]

Optional arguments:
  -h, --help                shows help message and exits 
  -o, --output              The path to the output pack file, directory, or file. If unspecified, will default next to the input path. 
  -t, --type                (Pack) The type of the output pack file. [default: "vpk"]
  --no-progress             Hide all progress bars. 
  -v, --version             (Pack) The version of the PCK/VPK. [default: "2"]
  -c, --chunksize           (Pack) The size of each archive in mb. [default: "200"]
  -m, --compression-method  (Pack) The method of compression to apply. BSP only supports "none" and "lzma".
                            ZIP supports all options. Option is unused for all other pack file types. [default: "none"]
  -x, --compression-level   (Pack) The level of compression to apply. (BSP, VPK v54, and ZIP only). [default: "5"]
  --gen-md5-entries         (Pack) Generate MD5 hashes for each file (VPK v2, v54 only). 
  --add-file                (Modify) Add the specified file to the pack file with the given path. [nargs: 2] [may be repeated]
  --add-dir                 (Modify) Add the specified directory to the pack file with the given path. [nargs: 2] [may be repeated]
  --remove-file             (Modify) Remove the specified file at the given path from the pack file. [may be repeated]
  --remove-dir              (Modify) Remove the specified directory at the given path from the pack file. [may be repeated]
  -p, --preload             (Pack) If a file's extension is in this list, the first kilobyte will be
                            preloaded in the directory FPX/VPK. Full file names are also supported here
                            (i.e. this would preload any files named README.md or files ending in vmt:
                            "-p README.md vmt"). It preloads materials by default to match Valve behavior. [nargs: 0 or more] [default: {"vmt"}]
  -s, --single-file         (Pack) Pack all files into the directory FPX/VPK (single-file build).
                            Breaks the pack file if its size will be >= 4gb! 
  -e, --extract             (Extract) Extracts the given file or directory, or the entire pack file.
                            If given a file path, it will try to read that file and save it to the output path.
                            If given a path ending in a forward slash, it will try to extract that directory
                            to the given output directory.
                            If given a single slash, it will extract the entire pack file under the given output
                            directory. [default: "/"]
  --gen-keypair             (Generate) Generate files containing public/private keys with the specified name.
                            DO NOT SHARE THE PRIVATE KEY FILE WITH ANYONE! Move it to a safe place where it
                            will not be shipped. 
  --file-tree               (Preview) Prints the file tree of the given pack file to the console. 
  -k, --sign                (Pack) Sign the output VPK with the key in the given private key file (v2 only).
                            (Sign) Sign the VPK with the key in the given private key file (v2 only). 
  --verify-checksums        (Verify) Verify the pack file's checksums. Can be "files", "overall", or "all" (without quotes). 
  --verify-signature        (Verify) Verify the pack file's signature if it exists. 
  --decryption-key          Use the specified hex sequence to decrypt a pack file. Ignored if unnecessary. 

Program details:                                               
                    /$$                       /$$ /$$   /$$    
                   | $$                      | $$|__/  | $$    
 /$$    /$$/$$$$$$ | $$   /$$  /$$$$$$   /$$$$$$$ /$$ /$$$$$$  
|  $$  /$$/$$__  $$| $$  /$$/ /$$__  $$ /$$__  $$| $$|_  $$_/  
 \  $$/$$/ $$  \ $$| $$$$$$/ | $$$$$$$$| $$  | $$| $$  | $$    
  \  $$$/| $$  | $$| $$_  $$ | $$_____/| $$  | $$| $$  | $$ /$$
   \  $/ | $$$$$$$/| $$ \  $$|  $$$$$$$|  $$$$$$$| $$  |  $$$$/
    \_/  | $$____/ |__/  \__/ \_______/ \_______/|__/   \____/ 
         | $$                                                  
         | $$             version v5.0.0-beta.4
         |__/                                                  
                                                               
Created by craftablescience. Contributors and libraries used are
listed in CREDITS.md. VPKEdit is licensed under the MIT License.


